Guide to the National Association of Manufactures Pamphlets 1945-1969
National Association of Manufactures Pamphlets
- NAM Publications, 1959; Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Item 14: Toward the Five-Year Goal, Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. February 1956. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Monopoly Power, Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Item 16: Dealing with Employees as Individuals, Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. October 1956. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Settling Complaints in the Non-Unionized Operation, Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. December 1957. Item is in English.
- NAM Publications, 1956-1958; Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: College Debate Kit, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. 1957-1958. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: A Monograph Discussing the Major Aspects of the Intercollegiate Debate Issue, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. October 1957. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Spotlight on Union Activities, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. January 1958. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Moral and Ethical Standards in Labor and Management, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: Check Points for Sound Collective Bargaining, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. November 1958. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Favorable Business Climate, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: What America Thinks- Forced Unionism vs. Right to Work, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. October 1958. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: NAM Motion Pictures, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 9: Organized Labor and the Antitrust Laws, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. March 1956. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Suggestion Plans, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. 11/19/1956. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Selected NAM Publications Dealing with Employee Relations, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 12: What is the NAM?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 13: Letter, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. June 24, 1958. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Capital Formation Key to Tomorrow's Prosperity, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 15: College Lecture Series, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 16: How the Ford-General Motors Settlement Affects the Collective Bargaining Position of Individual Companies, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. July 14, 1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Employee Relations Division, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. March 16, 1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: The Guaranteed Annual Wage-As an Issue-As a Reality, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 19: Some Major Labor Problems Looming Ahead in 1957, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. January 1957. Item is in English.
  - Item 20: The Changing Pace of Labor-Management Relations, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By Milton C. Lightner. March 10, 1958. Item is in English.
  - Item 21: Improving Human Relations, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. November 1956. Item is in English.
  - Item 22: Employers' Rights and Obligations under the Taft-Hartley Act, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. July 1956. Item is in English.
- NAM Publications, 1960; Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Missing Links in Labor-Management Relations, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By Edward Maher. February 25, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Dealing with Employees as Individuals, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. March 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Labor-Management Cooperation and its Meaning for Economic Growth, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. February 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Automation A Background Memorandum, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By Edward I. Maher. April 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Report on Employment of Mature Workers, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. September 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Industrial Medical Programs for Smaller Plants, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. 12/5/1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: The Emerging Economic Problems of the 1960s, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. January 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Productivity A Measure of Economic Progress, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. November 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Automation A Prime Source for More and Better Jobs, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Item 10: NAM News, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. 1/1/1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: A Look at the "Agency Shop", Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Item 12: NAM Basic Policy Positions on Industrial Relations, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Item 13: Employee Handbooks, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
- NAM Publications, 1961; Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Unemployment Causes and Cures, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. April 1961. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Meeting the Challenge of Automation through Sound Industrial Relations, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Item 3: Union Impact on Salaried Personnel, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Item 4: Union Excesses, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Item 5: Mobilizing Management for Changing Times, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Item 6: Creating More Jobs..Now, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Item 7: Industry and the Handicapped, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
    By John W. McGovern. April 28, 1961. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Dos and Don'ts for Mature Job Seekers, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Item 9: Labor-Management Developments- Challenge to the Nation, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
- NAM Publications, 1962; Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: The Productive Years- Ages 45-65, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 2: The Productive Years- Ages 45-65, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 3: Economic Implications of Union Power, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. June 1962. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Economic Implications of Union Power, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 5: The Productive Years-Ages 45-65, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. Copy 3. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Statesmanship in Industrial Relations, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 7: Employment Opportunities of Youth, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. March 1962. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Controlling the Cost of Group Medical Benefits, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
    By Benjamin B. Kendrick. 11/30/1962. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: News from 67th Annual Congress of American Industry, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 10: Productivity and Production in Industry, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. October 1962. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Industry's Profits, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 12: Industrial Research and Development, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 13: Wages and Prices in an Industrial Economy, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 14: A Comparison of Three Economic Systems, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 15: Human Relations and Efficient Production, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 16: Do the Seniority Rights of Employees Survive an Expired Contract?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 17: Industry-Organization and Employees, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. May 1962. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: Special Bibliography of NAM Industrial Relations, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
- NAM Publications, 1963; Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Union Power and the Public Interest, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 2: Examples of NAM Action to Meet Problems of Industrial Relations, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 3: Toward Wider Job Vistas for the Physically Impaired, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 4: Satisfying the Salaried Employee, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 5: Management Views Profit, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. August 8, 1963. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Who Profits from Profit, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. May 1963. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Summary of Industry Believes, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 8: Where Labor Unions Get Their Power?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By J. Mack Swigert. January 21, 1963. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: The Growth of American Industry, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. November 1963. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Medical Care: Voluntary or Mandatory, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. August 1963. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Union Demands for Job Security, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 12: Hiring Handicapped People, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. December 1, 1964. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: What is at Stake in a Shorter Work Week?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 14: NAM NLRB Meetings, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. April 9 ,1964. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Those Unemployment Statistics, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 16: The Changes Ahead in Management's Attitude Toward Labor Legislation, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By Tracy H. Ferguson. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Compulsory Arbitration of Industrial Disputes in Foreign Countries, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 18: NAM Law Department Reviews Civil Rights Act of 1964, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. July 1964. Item is in English.
  - Item 19: Curing the Double Tax Problem, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 20: Employee Displacement Minimizing its Adverse Effects, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
- NAM Publications (1 of 2), 1964; Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Solutions to Employee Problems Case Study File, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
- NAM Publications (2 of 2), 1964; Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
- NAM Publications, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  N. D.
  - Item 1: Labor Relations Today and Tomorrow, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 2: Better Communications mean Better Teamwork, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 3: Featherbeddingdrag on economic progress, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 4: Clergy-Industry Understandingas developed by NAM, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 5: The Top 10 of Safety, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 6: 20 Questions about the Rights to Work, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 7: Unionism: Voluntary or Involuntary?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 8: Do You Still have the Right to Run Your Plant?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 9: Gaining Acceptance for the Industrial Relations Function, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
    By R.E. Palenchar. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Fringes: Benefits or Burdens, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
    By Warren A. Lacke. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: What's Wrong with Labor Arbitration?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 12: Profitability Quotients in Human Relations, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
    By Louis R. Mobley. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Three's a Crowd, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
    By H.C. Lumb. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Employee Understanding of a Free Market Economy, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
    By L.C. Michelon. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Making an Audit of Salaried Personnel Practices, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 16: Job Evaluation, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
    By A. Lee Belcher. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Factors to Consider in Establishing a Profit-Sharing Plan, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 18: Making an Audit of Salaried Personnel Practices, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 19: Who's Too Small for a Health Program?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
- NAM Publications (1 of 2), 1965; Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Double Taxation of Dividends, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. May 1965. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: What is at Stake in a Shorter Work Week?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. January 1965. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: A New Start on the Double Tax Problem, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Item 4: Tax Treatment of Dividends, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
    By Milton C. Leontiades. May 1965. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: The People's Sector, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
    By Richard M. Nixon. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Industry Moves Forward, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Item 7: What Price Compulsory Unionism?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
    By C.W. Anderson. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Summary Analysis of Procedural Regulations of the EEOC, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. July 14, 1965. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Focus on Industrial Relations, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Item 10: Congress Asked: Save 14(b), Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. June 21, 1965. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Educators Look at the Minimum Wage, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Item 12: The Press Looks At Union Power and the Public Interest, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Item 13: How do People Grow in a Business Organization?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Item 14: Is Compulsory Arbitration the Answer to Labor Conflict?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. August 1965. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Industry Looks at Labor-Managament Relations Today and Tomorrow, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
    By W.P. Gullander. October 1965. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: "Right to Work": Should 14b Be Repealed?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. Spring 1965. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Fact File on Penalty Rates for Overtime, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Item 18: Fact File on Voluntary Unionism, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Item 19: Fact File on the Shorter Work Week, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
- NAM Publications (2 of 2), 1965; Publication (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Fact File on the Impact of Minimum Wages on Employment, Publication (Box 3, Folder 14)
- NAM Publications, 1955-1967; Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Inflation The Silent Tax, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. December 8, 1967. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Questions and Answers about the Guaranteed Annual Wage, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Item 3: How Our Business System Operates, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Item 4: Labor Monopolyand its Implications to a Free Society, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Dr. Leo Wolman. December 9, 1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: What Organized Labor Expects of Management, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By George Meany. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: News from the NAM, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By William F. Knowland. Press Release 12/10/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Major Trends in Collective Bargaining, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. Press Release 12/9/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: What Price Gaw-Sub?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By George F. Kohn. Press Release December 9, 1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: So People May Prosper, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Henry G. Riter. Press Release 12/7/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: The Carrot Instead of the Stick, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Sinclair Weeks. Press Release 12/7/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Political Requirements for Prosperity, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Hubert H. Humphrey. Press Release December 7, 1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: The Outlook for Disarmament and Peace, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Harold E. Stassen. Press Release 12/7/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Taxes and Freedom, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By WM J. Grede. Press Release 12/7/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: The Causes of Prosperity and Jobs, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Kenneth R. Miller. Press Release 12/7/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Investment Spending and Economic Growth, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Item 16: The Effect of American Prosperity Behind the Iron Curtain, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Harrison Salisbury. Press Release 12/8/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: The Impact of Asian Economies on United States Industry, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Arthur B. Foye. Press Release 12/8/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: The Periscope on International Affairs, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By National Association of Manufacturers. Press Release 12/8/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 19: The Aftermath of Geneva, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Hon. Anthony Nutting. Press Release 12/8/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 20: Patterns of Spiritual Values, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Dr. Louis H. Evans. Press Release 12/8/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 21: Where do we Stand on Freedom?, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Cola G. Parker. Press Release 12/8/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 22: The Pattern of People's Thinking, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Samuel Lubell. Press Release 12/8/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 23: Morality vs. Legality, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Cameron Hawley. Press Release 12/8/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 24: Federal Assistance for School Plant Construction, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Adrian Swift. Press Release 12/9/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 25: A Case Against Federal Aid, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Dr. Adam S. Bennion. Press Release 12/9/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 26: How Industry can Assist Education Develop More and Better Scientists and Engineers, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Robert C. Sprague. Press Release 12/9/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 27: What Industry Expects from Organized Labor, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Charles R. Sligh, Jr. Press Release 12/9/1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 28: Address by George Meany, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By George Meany. 12/9/1955. Item is in English.